<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>sound.risd.edu </title>
    <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://sound.risd.edu" />
    <updated>2018-12-07T06:54:18-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>shawn greenlee</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://sound.risd.edu</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Stephen Vitiello lecture | October 11, 2018</title>
        <author>
            <name>shawn greenlee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/stephen-vitiello-lecture-or-october-11-2018.html"/>
        <id>https://sound.risd.edu/stephen-vitiello-lecture-or-october-11-2018.html</id>
            <category term="News"/>

        <updated>2018-10-08T17:45:10-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/12/vit2.png" alt="" />
                     October 11th, 1-2pm RISD Museum Chace Center Auditorium Stephen Vitiello is an electronic musician and media artist. CD releases&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/12/vit2.png" alt="" />
                <p><img class="post__image--wide" src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/12/stephen2.png" width="2750" height="2680"></p>
<p> </p>
<p>October 11th, 1-2pm RISD Museum Chace Center Auditorium<br><br>Stephen Vitiello is an electronic musician and media artist. CD releases have been published by New Albion Records, Sub Rosa, 12k and Room 40. His sound installations and multi-channel works are in the permanent collections of the Museum of Modern Art, the Whitney Museum and the Museum of Contemporary Art, Lyon. Exhibitions include a site-specific work for NYC’s High Line, “Soundings: A Contemporary Score,” at the Museum of Modern Art; the 2002 Whitney Biennial; and the 2006 Biennial of Sydney. Over the last 25 years, Vitiello has collaborated with such artists and musicians as Pauline Oliveros, Ryuichi Sakamoto, Taylor Deupree, Joan Jonas, Julie Mehretu and Steve Roden. Vitiello has been awarded a Guggenheim Fellowship for “Fine Arts,” a Creative Capital grant for “Emerging Fields” and an Alpert/Ucross Award for Music. In 2012, Australian Television produced the documentary, Stephen Vitiello: Listening With Intent. Originally from New York, Vitiello is now based in Richmond, VA where he is a professor, and interim chair in the department of Kinetic Imaging at Virginia Commonwealth University. <br><br><a href="http://www.stephenvitiello.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">http://www.stephenvitiello.com</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Sensel interview</title>
        <author>
            <name>shawn greenlee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/sensel-interview.html"/>
        <id>https://sound.risd.edu/sensel-interview.html</id>
            <category term="News"/>

        <updated>2018-10-01T23:44:56-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/10/sensel.png" alt="" />
                    Sensel (a company specializing in high-resolution, pressure-sensitive, touch technology) recently conducted an interview with Shawn Greenlee (Associate Professor, EFS). RISD's&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/10/sensel.png" alt="" />
                <p><a href="https://sensel.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sensel</a> (a company specializing in high-resolution, pressure-sensitive, touch technology) recently conducted an interview with Shawn Greenlee (Associate Professor, EFS).  RISD's new spatial audio studio is discussed. </p>
<p>Read here: <a href="https://sensel.com/blogs/news/interview-shawn-greenlee" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://sensel.com/blogs/news/interview-shawn-greenlee</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>RISD Weekend demo | October 6, 2018</title>
        <author>
            <name>shawn greenlee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/risd-weekend.html"/>
        <id>https://sound.risd.edu/risd-weekend.html</id>
            <category term="News"/>

        <updated>2018-10-02T00:00:22-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/9/pvd.png" alt="" />
                    As part of the 2018 RISD Weekend events, Associate Professor of Experimental &amp; Foundation Studies Shawn Greenlee will demonstrate the capabilities of RISD's&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/9/pvd.png" alt="" />
                <p>As part of the <a href="http://risdweekend.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2018 RISD Weekend events</a>, Associate Professor of Experimental &amp; Foundation Studies Shawn Greenlee will demonstrate the capabilities of RISD's new spatial audio studio.  </p>
<p>Register for a session at the following links:</p>
<p>Session 1: <a href="http://risdweekend.com/reunion/#risd-revealed-ambisonic-sound-studio-session-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">October 6, 11:30am: RISD Revealed | Ambisonic Sound Studio </a></p>
<p>Session 2: <a href="http://risdweekend.com/reunion/#risd-revealed-ambisonic-sound-studio-session-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">October 6, 1:30pm: RISD Revealed | Ambisonic Sound Studio</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Reservations</title>
        <author>
            <name>shawn greenlee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/sas-reservations.html"/>
        <id>https://sound.risd.edu/sas-reservations.html</id>
            <category term="Spatial audio studio"/>

        <updated>2018-10-01T23:52:51-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/8/" alt="" />
                    click to log inUse of the studio is restricted to students enrolled in hosted courses and the associated faculty and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/8/" alt="" />
                <p class="msg msg--success align-left"><strong><a href="http://efs.bookedscheduler.com/Web/schedule.php?sid=13" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">click to log in</a></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Use of the studio is restricted to students enrolled in hosted courses and the associated faculty and staff.</li>
<li>Access to studio and reservation system is granted after an introductory lesson.</li>
<li>As part of coursework, students must learn to troubleshoot common problems.</li>
<li>There is no on-call support for 25.4 loudspeaker array. Submit a <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/7">support ticket</a> if a problem occurs.</li>
<li>Please review the <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/6">studio rules and guidelines</a>. Failure to adhere to these policies can result in revoked access.</li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Help </title>
        <author>
            <name>shawn greenlee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/sas-help.html"/>
        <id>https://sound.risd.edu/sas-help.html</id>
            <category term="Spatial audio studio"/>

        <updated>2018-10-01T23:52:56-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/7/" alt="" />
                    click to submit support ticket 
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/7/" alt="" />
                <p class="msg--highlight msg  msg--success align-left"><strong><a href="https://goo.gl/forms/LyAt2oGCibTXr0O43" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">click to submit support ticket</a></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>As part of coursework, students must learn to troubleshoot common problems.</li>
<li>By submitting a ticket, you will alert studio management of problems encountered. These will be addressed as soon as possible. Support tickets are reviewed daily.</li>
<li>There is no on-call support for 25.4 loudspeaker array.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>General rules and guidelines</title>
        <author>
            <name>shawn greenlee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/sas-rules.html"/>
        <id>https://sound.risd.edu/sas-rules.html</id>
            <category term="Spatial audio studio"/>

        <updated>2018-10-01T23:53:00-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/6/" alt="" />
                    Usage Access SupportThere is no on-call support for 25.4 loudspeaker array. Submit a support ticket if a problem occurs.As part&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/6/" alt="" />
                <p><strong>Usage</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Do not move or reposition the 25.4 array loudspeakers in any way. The system is calibrated to exact positions.  </li>
<li>The permitted types of studio work are computer-based / electronic media production.</li>
<li>The studio is a clean space. No materials or tools that produce dust or fumes are allowed. Fabrication should be done elsewhere.</li>
<li>Do not hang anything from the ceiling grid or speakers.</li>
<li>Do not pin, tape, or mount anything in any way to the walls or acoustic panels.</li>
<li>Do not leave or store anything in the studio. Items left will be discarded.</li>
<li>Do not remove equipment or furniture from the studio.</li>
<li>Keep any food or drinks in seminar area, away from computers and equipment. Please clean up. Take trash to bins outside of studio.</li>
<li>The tables and chairs in the seminar area can be rearranged to accommodate usage needs. Please return to default state.</li>
<li>Installations require special permission from studio management and coordination with faculty of studio courses.</li>
<li>Work conducted in the studio may not cause or threaten physical harm to its occupants, equipment, or facilities.</li>
<li>Failure to adhere to these policies can result in revoked access.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Access</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Use of the studio must be scheduled with the <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/8">reservation system</a>. Reservations can be made up until the current time. People that drop-in without making a reservation can be bumped. </li>
<li>Use of the studio is restricted to students enrolled in hosted courses and the associated faculty and staff.</li>
<li>Access to studio and reservation system is granted after an introductory lesson.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Support</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>There is no on-call support for 25.4 loudspeaker array. Submit a <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/7">support ticket</a> if a problem occurs.</li>
<li>As part of coursework, students must learn to troubleshoot common problems.</li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Hosted courses</title>
        <author>
            <name>shawn greenlee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/sas-courses.html"/>
        <id>https://sound.risd.edu/sas-courses.html</id>
            <category term="Spatial audio studio"/>

        <updated>2018-10-01T23:53:04-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/5/" alt="" />
                    Sonic Practices DM-3104: Fall 2018 / Spring 2019 Mark Cetilia, Andrea Pensado Sonic Practices is a graduate-level research group focused&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/5/" alt="" />
                <p><strong>Sonic Practices</strong><br>DM-3104: Fall 2018 / Spring 2019<br><em>Mark Cetilia, Andrea Pensado</em><br>Sonic Practices is a graduate-level research group focused on acoustic, electronic, and/or computer-based means of sound production and reception. Participants explore audio culture and technology while developing experimental approaches to composition, performance, recording, and/or listening. Areas of investigation include, but are not limited to: audio programming languages, embedded/mobile computing for sound and music, spatial audio, sound synthesis, audio electronics, sonification and auditory display, electroacoustic music composition and improvisation, field recording and soundscape studies, sound installation and performance, and sonic interaction design. Each semester, course content changes in response to a new unifying theme upon which students base individual and team-based research projects. Meetings consist of discussions, workshops, critiques, and collaborations that support students' individual inquiries, the exchange of ideas, and the exploration of research methodologies.</p>
<p><br><strong>Of Sound and Vision</strong><br>CTC 2007: Wintersession 2019<br><em>Mark Cetilia</em><br>This intensive studio course investigates computational approaches to generating sound and image in real time. Precedents from experimental film and video, as well as sound, installation, and performance art will be examined in relationship both to human perception and the students' artistic practice. The course will include discussion of key historical works and texts, hands-on demonstrations and in-class projects, as well as critical engagement with new works by class members. Students will use programming environments such as Max and its object libraries for sound and video, MSP and Jitter, to explore the creative and expressive potentials of an intermedia production practice, culminating in the development of a larger work that incorporates knowledge gained throughout the course.</p>
<p><br><strong>Spatial Audio</strong><br>CTC-2006: Spring 2019<br><em>Shawn Greenlee</em><br>Spatial Audio focuses on the creation of immersive 3D sound experiences. In this course, students analyze and explore how the sensation of space is activated in the listener by making works using spatial audio techniques. These methods include high-order ambisonics, vector-based amplitude panning, multichannel surround, and binaural audio, among others. Throughout the semester, a series of exercises addressing technical and theoretical issues provide students with the necessary experience to produce midterm and final projects. Coursework involves computational approaches to sound design and composition, with instruction in the audio programming language Max and digital audio workstations, i.e. Ableton Live and Reaper. Students have recurring access to a 25-channel loudspeaker array for the development of works. Readings from psychology, philosophy, the arts, and sound studies support class discussions and critiques. Students will need a laptop computer (Mac or Windows) and a Max software license (educational pricing available from cycling74.com). Previous experience with digital audio software recommended.</p>
<p><br><strong>Digital + Media Studio/Seminar and Thesis Project courses</strong><br>Fall 2018 / Spring 2019<br>Graduate-level core studio coursework for the D+M MFA program. D+M students can receive training and gain access to the sound lab at 15 Westminster for relevant projects.</p>
<p><br><strong>Programming Sound: Performance Systems</strong><br>Returning in Fall 2019<br><em>Instructor TBA</em><br>Programming Sound: Performance Systems focuses on programming and designing computer-based systems for sound art and music performance. Centered on the dataflow programming language, Pure Data (Pd), the course will be of substantial benefit to students who desire a rigorous and fast-moving foundation in algorithmic approaches to sound design. The course simultaneously facilitates explorations in sound synthesis, audio signal processing, electronics, mobile platforms, gesture-based human computer interaction, and instrument building with microcontrollers and sensors. Coursework involves weekly homework in the form of online lectures and exercises with class sessions reserved for demonstrations, workshops, and project assistance. The course emphasizes modularity and reuse of code. Students will present their work in a public concert during the last week of the semester. Additional notes: In order to conduct work in this course, students will need a laptop computer running a recent OS: Mac, Windows, or Linux. Previous programming experience is recommended, but not required.<br><br></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Seminar area</title>
        <author>
            <name>shawn greenlee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/sas-seminar.html"/>
        <id>https://sound.risd.edu/sas-seminar.html</id>
            <category term="Spatial audio studio"/>

        <updated>2018-10-03T00:16:36-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/4/" alt="" />
                    The seminar area of the studio is for flexible use and supports audio-visual presentations independent from the 25.4 loudspeaker array.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/4/" alt="" />
                <p>The seminar area of the studio is for flexible use and supports audio-visual presentations independent from the 25.4 loudspeaker array.</p>
<div class="gallery"   >
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/4/gallery/m11_seminar1.jpg" ><img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/4/gallery/m11_seminar1-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="240"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/4/gallery/m11_seminar2.jpg" ><img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/4/gallery/m11_seminar2-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="240"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/4/gallery/m11_seminar3.jpg" ><img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/4/gallery/m11_seminar3-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="240"></a></figure>
</div>
<p>Equipment includes:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://pro.sony/en_BA/products/medium-displays/fw-65bz35f" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">65" Sony Bravia 4K TV display</a> FW-65BZ35F, wall mounted</li>
<li><a href="https://www.genelec.com/studio-monitors/8000-series-studio-monitors/8050b-studio-monitor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2 Genelec 8050B studio monitors</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.crestron.com/Products/Video/All-In-One-Solutions/DigitalMedia-Presentation-Switchers/DMPS3-4K-150-C" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Crestron 4K DigitalMedia Presentation System DMPS3-4K-150-C </a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.extron.com/product/dmp44lc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Extron DMP 44LC, 4x4 digital matrix processor</a></li>
<li><a href="https://proav.roland.com/global/products/vr-50hd/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Roland VR-50HD, multi-format AV mixer </a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.allen-heath.com/ahproducts/zedi-10fx/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Allen&amp;Heath ZEDi 10FX USB 4x4 mixer</a></li>
<li>Video inputs, rack: HDMI, VGA</li>
<li>Audio inputs, rack: HDMI, 3.5mm, balanced XLR (line-level)</li>
<li>AV outputs, rack: HDMI, Assitive Listening System </li>
<li>Dry-erase, magnetic presentation boards </li>
<li><a href="https://www.hermanmiller.com/products/workspaces/collaborative-furniture/everywhere-tables/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8 HermanMiller Flip-Top tables</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.hermanmiller.com/products/seating/stacking-chairs/caper-stacking-chair/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">18 HermanMiller Caper chairs</a></li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Core software</title>
        <author>
            <name>shawn greenlee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/sas-software.html"/>
        <id>https://sound.risd.edu/sas-software.html</id>
            <category term="Spatial audio studio"/>

        <updated>2018-10-03T00:10:34-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/3/" alt="" />
                    This is a listing of the audio software (beyond the RISD coreware) installed on the main workstation. The rack workstation&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/3/" alt="" />
                <p>This is a listing of the audio software (beyond the RISD coreware) installed on the main workstation.<br> The rack workstation does not match this listing.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Programming</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://cycling74.com/products/max" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Max 8.0.0</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cycling74.com/products/max" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Max 7.3.5</a> </li>
<li><a href="https://supercollider.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Supercollider 3.9.3</a></li>
<li><a href="http://msp.ucsd.edu/software.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pd 0.48-1</a></li>
</ul>
<br>
<p><strong>DAW</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://reaper.fm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reaper 5.93</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.ableton.com/en/live/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ableton Live 10.0.2</a></li>
</ul>
<br>
<p><strong>Spatialization libraries and plugins</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>VST/AU <a href="https://www.noisemakers.fr" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Noisemakers Ambi Bundle HD 1.1</a></li>
<li>VST/AU <a href="http://gris.musique.umontreal.ca" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SpatGRIS</a> </li>
<li>VST <a href="http://www.matthiaskronlachner.com/?p=2015" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ambiX ambisonic 0.2.7 1st/3rd order</a></li>
<li>VST <a href="https://www.brucewiggins.co.uk/?page_id=78" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wigware, 1st/high order</a></li>
<li>VST <a href="https://facebook360.fb.com/spatial-workstation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fb360 Spatial Workstation 3.3b1</a></li>
<li>VST <a href="https://developers.google.com/resonance-audio/develop/vst-monitor/getting-started" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Resonance Audio 1.1.1</a></li>
<li>Reaper/JSFX <a href="http://www.ambisonictoolkit.net/download/reaper/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ambisonic Toolkit 1.0</a></li>
<li>Ableton Live <a href="http://www.envelop.us/software/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Envelop (E4L)</a></li>
<li>Supercollider <a href="http://www.ambisonictoolkit.net/download/supercollider/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ambisonic Toolkit 1.0</a></li>
<li>Max <a href="http://forumnet.ircam.fr/product/spat-en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IRCAM Spat 5.0.7</a></li>
<li>Max <a href="https://www.zhdk.ch/downloads-ambisonics-externals-for-maxmsp-5381" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ICST Ambisonic 2.3.2</a> </li>
<li>Max <a href="http://hoalibrary.mshparisnord.fr/en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CICM HOA Library 2.2</a></li>
<li>Max <a href="http://ico.bukvic.net/main/d4/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">D4 2.1.2</a></li>
<li>Max &amp; Pd <a href="http://www.zacharyseldess.com/miap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MIAP 1.2.2 </a></li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>25.4 loudspeaker array</title>
        <author>
            <name>shawn greenlee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/sas-array.html"/>
        <id>https://sound.risd.edu/sas-array.html</id>
            <category term="Spatial audio studio"/>

        <updated>2018-10-02T00:03:48-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/1/" alt="" />
                    The sound system consists of an array of 25 independently-addressable, full-range speakers in a hemisphere configuration, accompanied by 4 subwoofers.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/1/" alt="" />
                <p>The sound system consists of an array of 25 independently-addressable, full-range speakers in a hemisphere configuration, accompanied by 4 subwoofers.  A variety of spatial audio techniques are supported, including high order ambisonics, vector-based amplitude panning, multichannel surround, and 3D audio for immersive media.</p>
<div class="gallery"   >
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/1/gallery/m11_array1.jpg" ><img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/1/gallery/m11_array1-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="240"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/1/gallery/m11_array2.jpg" ><img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/1/gallery/m11_array2-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="240"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/1/gallery/m11_array3.jpg" ><img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/1/gallery/m11_array3-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="240"></a></figure>
</div>
<p>  <strong>Support documents (studio specific)</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/6">Studio rules and guidelines</a></li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Getting started and troubleshooting (in progress)</span></li>
<li><a href="media/files/m11_speakerNumbering.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Loudspeaker numbering</a></li>
<li><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1OcgXRTtTGmD_vEQxK_zaynicAR4NSGUk112rdJy8I0o/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Loudspeaker coordinates</a> (in progress)</li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">AVB routing (in progess)</span></li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Loudspeakers</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.genelec.com/studio-monitors/8000-series-studio-monitors/8050b-studio-monitor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">25 Genelec 8050B studio monitors</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.genelec.com/support-technology/previous-models/hts4b-home-theater-subwoofer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">4 Genelec HTS4B home theater subwoofers</a></li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Main workstation</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.apple.com/imac-pro/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">iMac Pro 27" 3.0 GHz 10-core Intel Xeon, 128GB RAM, 2TB SSD</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.ableton.com/en/push/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ableton Push 2 controller</a></li>
<li><a href="https://sensel.com/pages/morph" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sensel Morph controller w/ overlays</a></li>
<li><a href="http://motu.com/products/avb/8m" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MOTU 8M AVB interface</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.networksound.com/index.php/products/pbays/xlr" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Network Sound patchbay</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.azstudioworkstations.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Desk, custom AZ Studio Workstations</a></li>
<li><a href="https://pro.sony/en_BA/products/medium-displays/fw-55BZ35F" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">55" Sony Bravia 4K TV display</a> FW-55BZ35F, cart mounted</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Rack</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.apple.com/imac/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">iMac 27"</a> (desk)</li>
<li><a href="http://motu.com/products/avb/8m" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MOTU 8M AVB interface</a> (desk)</li>
<li><a href="http://motu.com/products/avb/1248" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MOTU 1248 AVB audio interface</a> </li>
<li><a href="http://motu.com/products/avb/24ai-24ao" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MOTU 24Ao AVB audio interface</a> </li>
<li><a href="http://motu.com/products/avb/avb-switch" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2 MOTU AVB switches</a></li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
