<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>sound.risd.edu </title>
    <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://sound.risd.edu" />
    <updated>2020-09-14T11:59:17-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>shawn greenlee</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://sound.risd.edu</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Spatial Audio Studio article on risd.edu | September 2019</title>
        <author>
            <name>shawn greenlee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/risdedu-feature.html"/>
        <id>https://sound.risd.edu/risdedu-feature.html</id>

        <updated>2019-12-05T08:57:24-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     Article on the first year of the Spatial Audio Studio: Sonic Practice on the Cutting Edge. Since opening last fall, the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><img class="post__image" src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/16/1561576413243_Spatial-audio-studio-for-sense-of-scale.jpg" alt="" width="4832" height="3222"></p>
<p>Article on the first year of the Spatial Audio Studio: <em>Sonic Practice on the Cutting Edge. </em>Since opening last fall, the spatial audio studio above the library has helped advance sound studies at RISD...</p>
<p> <a href="https://www.risd.edu/news/stories/spatial-audio-studio-inspires-sonic-innovation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.risd.edu/news/stories/spatial-audio-studio-inspires-sonic-innovation/</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Yasunao Tone - performance and lecture | April 3-4, 2019</title>
        <author>
            <name>shawn greenlee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/yasunao-tone-performance-and-lecture-or-april-3-4-2019.html"/>
        <id>https://sound.risd.edu/yasunao-tone-performance-and-lecture-or-april-3-4-2019.html</id>

        <updated>2019-03-12T22:56:48-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Performance: April 3, 7pm. Prov Wash Auditorium, 20 Washington PlaceLecture: April 4, 1pm. Spatial Audio Studio, 15 Westminster St., Mezzanine&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div><hr></div>
<img class="post__image" src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/15/tone.png" alt="" width="1279" height="1279">
<ul>
<li>Performance: April 3, 7pm. Prov Wash Auditorium, 20 Washington Place</li>
<li>Lecture: April 4, 1pm. Spatial Audio Studio, 15 Westminster St., Mezzanine floor, room M11</li>
</ul>
<p> <em>Sponsored by the Computation, Technology, and Culture concentration and the Digital+Media Department</em></p>
<p>Yasunao Tone (born 1935) is a Japanese-American artist, writer, theorist, and composer. According to critic Alan Cummings, he is “part of a whole generation of post-war iconoclasts who followed in the wake of John Cage's discovery of indeterminacy, determined to shake music and art out of their enslavement to the high art, romanticist ideals of the 19th century.” He co-founded Group Ongaku (Music group) in the early 1960s, has been active in the Fluxus movement since 1962, and has also been an organizer and participant in many important music and performance scenes including New York’s Downtown improvisors, and the European electronica experimentalists. An outstanding experimentalist, Yasunao coined the term "paramedia art" to describe his work, and his artistic inventions include prepared CD, interventions with an MP3 system and AI programm. Primarily a composer, Tone has worked in many media, creating pieces for electronics, computer systems, film, radio and television, as well as environmental art. His work is distinguished by conversion of text into music via images with analog and digital means, and with critique of medium in use (Music for 2CD Players, Solo for Wounded CD). Tone has presented concerts at the Kitchen, MoMA, the Guggenheim, Museum of Contemporary Art Barcelona, the Ars Electronica Festival, Centre George Pompidou, Sonic Lights in Amsterdam, ATP festivals and Lovebytes festivals, among many others. Select exhibitions include the Venice Biennale, numerous FLUXUS shows, "The Japanese Avant-garde since 1945" at the Guggenheim Museum, "Bitstreams" at the Whitney Museum, the Yokohama Triennale. Honors include the Ars Electronica Golden Nica award and the Foundation for Contemporary Arts award in music.</p>
<p id="mcetoc_1d5qfl6720" class="taFHO sc-jqCOkK jbhBLB">Video: <a href="https://vimeo.com/175305422" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Yasunao Tone: AI Deviation at ISSUE Project Room June 9th, 2016</a></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Derek Holzer - vector synthesis workshop and performance | March 19-21, 2019</title>
        <author>
            <name>shawn greenlee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/derek-holzer-vector-synthesis-workshop.html"/>
        <id>https://sound.risd.edu/derek-holzer-vector-synthesis-workshop.html</id>

        <updated>2019-03-12T22:55:37-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/14/kvant-green-1024x1024.png" alt="" />
                    On the evenings of March 19 and 20, Derek Holzer will lead a Vector Synthesis Workshop at RISD’s Spatial Audio Studio,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/14/kvant-green-1024x1024.png" alt="" />
                <hr>
<p>On the evenings of March 19 and 20, <a href="http://macumbista.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Derek Holzer</a> will lead a Vector Synthesis Workshop at RISD’s Spatial Audio Studio, sponsored by the <a href="https://ctc.risd.edu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Computation, Technology, and Culture</a> concentration.  <br><br>Basic experience with the programming languages <a href="https://cycling74.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Max</a> or <a href="https://puredata.info/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pd</a> is required. <br><br>When: March 19 at 7:00pm and March 20 at 6:30pm<br><br>Where: Spatial Audio Studio, 15 Westminster St., Mezzanine floor, room M11<br><br>Capacity is limited, please sign up here: <a href="https://goo.gl/forms/4aSlJC4OE7f5bHWz1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://goo.gl/forms/4aSlJC4OE7f5bHWz1</a><br><br>An e-mail will be sent to you by March 17 to confirm your spot.  Attendance on both evenings is recommended.<br><br>-----<br><br>DEREK HOLZER is a sound + light artist based in Helsinki &amp; Berlin, whose current interests include DIY electronics, audiovisual instrument building, the relationship between sound and space, media archaeology, and participatory art forms. He has performed live, taught workshops and created scores of unique instruments and installations since 2002 across Europe, North and South America, and New Zealand. <br><br><a href="http://macumbista.net/">http://macumbista.net/</a><br><a href="https://www.instagram.com/macumbista/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.instagram.com/macumbista/</a><br><br><br>-----<br><br>On <strong>Tuesday March 19</strong>, the workshop will start at 7pm and feature a lecture: A Media Archaeology of Vector Graphics. The development of any kind of media technology combines utopian and dystopian tendencies, and nowhere is that more true than in the development of computer vector graphics. Taking the activation of the AN/FSQ-7 computers at the heart of the SAGE (Semi-Automatic Ground Environment) defense stations in the United States in 1958 as its starting point, this talk explores the military/scientific legacy at the heart of modern computing and attempts by artists of the 50’s, 60’s, and 70’s to decouple these tools from their destructive origins.<br><br>-----<br><br>On <strong>Wednesday March 20</strong>, the workshop will start at 6:30pm.  The focus will be on Holzer's Vector Synthesis library, which uses the Pure Data programming environment to investigate the direct relationship between sound+image. With it, you can draw Lissajous figures, render simple two- and three-dimensional shapes, and process photographs and video into vector artwork which can be displayed on oscilloscopes using audio signals. These shapes can also be further modified in real time using external audio sources such as voice, amplified instruments, or electronic synthesizers. This talk will introduce the basic concepts and capabilities of this publicly-available, free and open source audio+visual library. <a href="https://github.com/macumbista/vectorsynthesis" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/macumbista/vectorsynthesis</a><br><br>-----<br><br>On <strong>Thursday night March 21</strong>, Derek Holzer will perform at <a href="http://www.machineswithmagnets.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Machines with Magnets</a> in Pawtucket, RI.  Further details can be found at the FB event page here: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/254381318802981/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.facebook.com/events/254381318802981/</a><br><br><img class="post__image" src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/14/03_19_poster-web-2.png" alt="" width="1100" height="1500"></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Olivia Block - performance and lecture | February 20-21, 2019</title>
        <author>
            <name>shawn greenlee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/olivia-block-performance-and-lecture.html"/>
        <id>https://sound.risd.edu/olivia-block-performance-and-lecture.html</id>

        <updated>2019-03-12T22:55:29-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/13/olivia1.png" alt="" />
                     Sponsored by the Computation, Technology, and Culture concentration and the Digital+Media Department Olivia Block is a composer and media&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/13/olivia1.png" alt="" />
                <hr>
<p><img class="post__image" src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/13/olivia2.png" alt="" width="2750" height="3750"></p>
<ul>
<li>Performance, February 20, 7pm. RISD Chace Center, Metcalf Auditorium</li>
<li>Lecture, February 21, 1pm. RISD D+M Department, CIT 4th floor</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Sponsored by the Computation, Technology, and Culture concentration and the Digital+Media Department</em></p>
<p>Olivia Block is a composer and media artist based in Chicago. Her recorded compositions combine field recordings, chamber instruments and electronic textures<em>,</em> and others. Block creates multimedia installations and performances utilizing field recordings, found sounds from micro cassette tapes, video, and curated 35mm slides. Block’s current work reflects her interests in site specificity, ethnographic sound, architecture, and found/archival materials from the 1950’s-1990’s. Block often performs her own solo pieces, utilizing electronically processed amplified objects, found recordings on tapes, and various techniques inside grand pianos. Her studio based compositions are published on And/Oar, Cut, Erstwhile, Glistening Examples, NNA, and Sedimental, among other labels. She has created site specific multi-speaker installations for The Sanitorium in Sokolowsko, Poland, The Jay Pritzker Pavilion in Millennium Park, Chicago, and the Olympics in Turin Italy, among others. She has performed and premiered pieces in festivals throughout America, Europe, Scandinavia, and Japan. Block has been interviewed on NPR’s Morning Edition, Wire Magazine, Musicworks Magazine, Blow Up, Chicago Reader, and many additional podcasts, publications and radio programs.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.oliviablock.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.oliviablock.net/</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Stephen Vitiello - lecture | October 11, 2018</title>
        <author>
            <name>shawn greenlee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sound.risd.edu/stephen-vitiello-lecture-or-october-11-2018.html"/>
        <id>https://sound.risd.edu/stephen-vitiello-lecture-or-october-11-2018.html</id>

        <updated>2019-03-12T22:03:36-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/12/vit2.png" alt="" />
                     October 11, 1pm. RISD Chace Center, Metcalf Auditorium Sponsored by the Computation, Technology, and Culture concentration and the Digital+Media&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/12/vit2.png" alt="" />
                <hr>
<p><img class="post__image--wide" src="https://sound.risd.edu/media/posts/12/stephen2.png" width="2750" height="2680"></p>
<p> </p>
<p>October 11, 1pm. RISD Chace Center, Metcalf Auditorium</p>
<p><em>Sponsored by the Computation, Technology, and Culture concentration and the Digital+Media Department</em></p>
<p>Stephen Vitiello is an electronic musician and media artist. CD releases have been published by New Albion Records, Sub Rosa, 12k and Room 40. His sound installations and multi-channel works are in the permanent collections of the Museum of Modern Art, the Whitney Museum and the Museum of Contemporary Art, Lyon. Exhibitions include a site-specific work for NYC’s High Line, “Soundings: A Contemporary Score,” at the Museum of Modern Art; the 2002 Whitney Biennial; and the 2006 Biennial of Sydney. Over the last 25 years, Vitiello has collaborated with such artists and musicians as Pauline Oliveros, Ryuichi Sakamoto, Taylor Deupree, Joan Jonas, Julie Mehretu and Steve Roden. Vitiello has been awarded a Guggenheim Fellowship for “Fine Arts,” a Creative Capital grant for “Emerging Fields” and an Alpert/Ucross Award for Music. In 2012, Australian Television produced the documentary, Stephen Vitiello: Listening With Intent. Originally from New York, Vitiello is now based in Richmond, VA where he is a professor, and interim chair in the department of Kinetic Imaging at Virginia Commonwealth University. <br><br><a href="http://www.stephenvitiello.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">http://www.stephenvitiello.com</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
